# **DRASHTI PATEL**

■ Kitchener, ON N2EOC5 ■ 5197216820 ■ driha.patel@gmail.com ■ **WWW:** <u>Bold Profile</u> ■

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Web Developer with passion for creating attractive and interactive websites meeting customer needs and exceeding expectations. Well-versed in developing custom WordPress themes and plugins. Excels in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP development. Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

### **SKILLS**

- Design User Interface
- Version Management
- GitHub
- website/Snippet development or customization
- Technical analysis
- Standard-compliant coding

- Web development projects
- Scripting languages: Python, JavaScript
- Front-end programming: HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Databases: Oracle, SQL server
- Responsive Design

### **WORK HISTORY**

### **ODOO WEB DEVELOPER** 11/2016 TO 12/2021

Serpent Consultancy Services Pvt. Ltd., Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India

- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user problems.
- Created powerful Content Management Systems to serve as interface for client.
- Developed user-friendly web forms with validation and error handling.
- Developed technical solutions required to accommodate specific user-facing assets
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress and other editing software.

#### FUNCTIONAL CONSULTANT 01/2022 TO 05/2022

Condi Group, Mississauga, ON

- Determined proper methodologies and procedures to use based upon project specifications.
- Developed diagrams to describe and lay out logical operational steps.
- Troubleshot incidents reported by end-users to schedule system changes and identify permanent solutions.
- Wrote effective documentation for each client system to deliver comprehensive sets of requirements and alignment with business objectives.
- Professionally interacted with clients to assess business requirements and determine software needs.

### PART-TIME NIGHT ASSOCIATE 04/2022 to 03/2023

Lowe's Home Improvement, Kitchener, ON

- Rotated stock and restocked shelves to maintain product availability and store appearance.
- Prioritized helping customers over completing other routine tasks in store.
- Helped customers locate products and checked store system for merchandise at other sites.

#### FULL-TIME GENERAL LABORER 09/2022 to 07/2023

Prodigy Personnel, Brantford, ON

- Read work orders to determine work assignments and equipment and materials needed.
- Loaded, unloaded, and moved material to and from storage and production areas.
- Performed quality checks on products and materials to identify any defects.
- Assisted team members with tasks that require group effort.
- Generated daily productivity records and assisted senior leadership during executive decisionmaking processes.
- Led inventory processes to minimize project lags.

## LINE LEAD 07/2023 to CURRENT

DHL Supply Chain, Brantford, ON

- Trained and monitored line associates to perform proper assembly techniques, apply best practices and comply with safety procedures.
- Followed daily production schedules for organized and on-time deliveries.
- Assisted in training new employees and implementing procedural changes.
- Communicated shift handover information to keep personnel aware of incomplete tasks.
- Prepared reports and technical documentation of day-to-day production processes.
- Post-Degree Certificate: Cloud Data Management, 04/2023
  Conestoga College Institute of Technology And Advanced Learning Kitchener, ON
- Master of Science: Information Technology And Computer Applications, 06/2015
  Ganpat University Gujarat, India
- Bachelor of Science: Information Technology And Computer Applications, 06/2013
  Ganpat University Gujarat, India

EDUCATION

•